Now that we've discussed topics,
トピックについてお話したので
let's talk about the messages transmitted over them.
ここではトピックへ送るメッセージについてお話します
Each ROS distribution comes with a wide variety of
それぞれの ROS distribution では 事前定義されたさまざまなメッセージタイプを
predefined message types which are available for your use.
使用することができます
There are message types for communicating physical quantities,
物理量を伝えるメッセージタイプとしては
such as positions, velocities,
位置 速度 加速度
accelerations, rotations, and durations.
回転 継続時間などがあります
There are also messages for communicating sensor readings,
また メッセージにはセンサー信号として
such as laser scans, images,
レーザースキャン イメージ
point clouds, inertial measurements, and more.
ポイントクラウド 慣性計測などがあります
The number of message types available in a full ROS install is actually quite staggering.
実際の ROS フルインストールで使用できるメッセージタイプの数は とても多いです
Doing a simple search in my system,
私のシステム内で簡単に検索したところ
I was able to count over 200 different message types.
200 以上の異なるメッセージタイプが見つかりました
However, even with so many useful message types available,
一方で それほど多くのメッセージタイプを使用できるとしても
there will still be times when you want to define your own.
ご自身で定義するとなれば その何倍にもなります
We'll tackle that later on in this lesson.
これについては このレッスンの後半で取り組みます
It's important to note that although
メッセージという名前から 単にテキストベースのコンテンツであると思いがちですが
the named messages would seem to imply text based contents,
あらゆる種類のデータがその中に含まれていることに
they can in fact contain any kind of data.
注意することが重要です
Here's an example of the message types associated with the topics we looked at earlier.
これが 前に学習したトピックに関連するメッセージタイプの例です
In this case, the topic called camera images is transporting
この場合 camera image と呼ばれるトピックでは
image messages from the camera node to the position estimator node.
画像メッセージをカメラノードから位置予測ノードへ転送します
The wheel encoder's topic is transporting rotation messages from
wheel encoder トピックは回転メッセージを
the wheel encoder node to the position estimator node and so on.
ホイールエンコーダーノードから位置予測ノードなどへ転送します